Cristóbal Carnero Liñán

☐ +34 655 52 79 11 ☑ ccarnerolinan@gmail.com ⑤ https://cristobal.dev 12th February, 1981



Summary

AWS Solutions Architect certified with more than 10 years of professional experience designing, building and deploying server-side solutions in the cloud, for different industries like management consulting, energy, video games, and university research groups. Expertise in web APIs, Data Engineering and DevOps.

Education

2009-2011 Master in Software Engineer and Artificial Intelligence, Universidad de Málaga.

2002 – 2007 Computer and Software Engineering, Universidad de Málaga. 5-year university degree. Bachelor Thesis approved with Special Distinction.

Certifications

* AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate, Amazon Web Services.

Experience

Since Nov Cathedral Software, Senior Data Engineer & DevOps.

2018 - Work for one of the biggest management consulting firm.

- Develop backend services for web applications using Django REST Framework for API,
 Celery for background tasks, and Django Channels for notitifications.
- Work with Data Science team in order to design and implement cloud architecture solutions in both AWS & Azure, using Terraform.
- Implement continuos integration with different stacks: CircleCI, Azure DevOps, Docker, Helm, Kubernetes.

Feb 2018 - Virtually Live, Senior Server Engineer & DevOps.

Nov 2018 – Independently responsible for designing full real-time data pipeline architecture from the ingestion of telemetry from live events (*Formula E*), processing, and serve the output stream data to mobile games at scale.

- Implement the key parts of the architecture in Python using technologies like ZeroMQ, Kafka and Tornado.
- Work closely with Data Science team to provide a stream processing framework using Apache Heron for their needs.
- Deployment of a Kubernetes cluster in AWS using Ansible, including hosted applications using Helm, and continuos integration with Jenkins.
- Contributions to open source project Apache Heron in order to fix deployment to Kubernetes and complete its documentation.
- Work with R&D department designing and developing a prototype for a real time computer vision app using deep learning with Keras.

2017-2018 Cathedral Software, Senior Software Engineer.

- Work on the data pipeline of the business intelligence platform of one of the largest travel web companies.
- Develop ETL in Airflow to calculate KPIs and provide reporting capabilities for internal tools of the client company.
- Responsible to design and develop backend solution to provide real time chat and other features to mobile app using Tornado.

2015 - 2017 VATIA Energía, Software Engineering Manager.

- Responsible to design and develop a web platform for automatic Virtual Energetic Audit and Energetic Benchmarking.
- Develop key parts of the system: Node.js APIs, background tasks using Celery for monitoring, and data analysis/reporting with Pandas and Matplotlib.
- Responsible for recruiting technical staff: write job descriptions, qualify resumes, interview candidates and provide assessments.

2011 – 2013 Melomics Media, Backend Developer, DevOps.

- Server side development and deployment of a massive online repository of computer generated music, with search, streaming, purchases and public API.
- Administration of a cluster of Debian servers.
- Development of automatic video edition software with additional post-processing capabilities as chroma key, filters, titles, subtitles, publishing,...
- Technologies: Python, web.py, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Memcached. APIs: Paypal, Google Wallet, Facebook, Google+.

2009 – 2011 Universidad de Málaga, Researcher.

- Computer vision research in the department of "Computational Intelligence and Image Analysis", managed by José Muñoz Perez and Enrique Dominguez Merino.
- Technologies: Python, C++, OpenCV, cvBlob, Matlab, Octave.

2007 – 2009 Tedial S.L., Backend Developer, System Administrator.

- Server-side media storage technologies.
- Authentication, authorization, and access control with LDAP.
- Management software for surveillance cameras.
- Deployment of software and administration of several SuSE Enterprise Server client installations.
- Technologies: C++, Python, Oracle, SOAP.

2005 – 2006 Novasoft, Software and Web Developer.

- Educational video games in Flash.
- Started in a one month scholarship, but then the company hired for a longer project.
- Technologies: Flash, ActionScript, HTML, Javascript.

Personal projects

Since 2020 EnRemo.to, https://enremo.to.

- Directory of tools for remote working developed during COVID-19 as a weekend No-Code project.
- Job offers for remote positions in companies based in Spain.
- Blog about remote working.

Since 2016 Mukabe, https://mukabe.com.

- *Mukabe* is the new way of navigate through information, the new social and online organization, and the new way to get visibility for you, your projects or your company.
- Technologies: Python, Django, Celery, Redis, ElasticSearch, Ansible, Fabric, AWS, Social APIs (Instagram, Facebook, Google+), HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery.

Since 2015 RegaloInteligente, http://regalointeligente.com.

- Search engine of gifts with parameters like gender and age, and filter for prices.
- Web and Android applications. Twitter bot with auto posting and automatic reply. Telegram
- Technologies: Python, Pyramid, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Amazon Product Advertising API, Twitter API, Telegram Bot API, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery.

Free Software Projects

2014 – 2015 WooDPD, https://es.wordpress.org/plugins/woodpd/.

WordPress Plugin to integrate DPD purchases in WooCommerce.

2009 – 2012 **cvBlob**, https://github.com/cristobalcl/cvblob.

Blob library for OpenCV, widely used in computer vision and robotic research.

Languages

Spanish Native

English Fluent

Qualities

Computer skills

Languages: Python, Bash script, Elixir (learning).

Testing: TDD (Test-driven development), unittest, pytest, Selenium.

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Redis.

Frameworks: Django, Django REST framework, Celery, Airflow.

Infrastruc- Kubernetes, AWS, Azure, DigitalOcean.

ture:

Deployment: Docker, Helm, Jenkins, Terraform, Ansible, Supervisor, Nginx.

Data Pandas, Keras, Jupyter.

Science:

Environ- Vim/NeoVim, Make, Git.

ments:

Personal skills

- Engineering Ability to find creative solutions.
 - Strong analytical, able to anticipate issues, resolve concerns and improve efficiency.
 - Care of coding standards and best practices.
 - Eager to learn and develop new skills.

- Others Ability to work without direct supervision.
 - Great written communication skills (wide experience in both Spanish and English).

Interests

GNU/Linux, free software, image processing, computer vision, computer graphics, artificial intelligence.